jmccormack215@gmail.com // 646.509.0368 // jessmccormack.com

I am an experienced, successful leader in project management, marketing and graphic design. Through effective collaboration with clients and internal teams, I balance strategy and creative stewardship, while meeting the schedule and scope of each project. I thrive in a team environment, producing results and pushing ideas further. I have worked for Fortune 500 advertising agencies and a handful of specialized design firms. In addition to global brands like Canon, Neiman Marcus, Tylenol and Disney, I have also worked with hundreds of clients to design custom branding, marketing and packaging programs.

EXPERIENCE

Major Account Manager // Montagne Custom Packaging // Atlanta, GA // 2017-present

- + Packaging and display system design for the luxury jewelry industry
- + Customer acquisition and sales through trade shows, digital marketing outreach and cold calls
- + Production oversight with our manufacturing factories in China and Thailand
- + Global supply chain logistics for raw materials, imported final goods and customer warehousing/distribution
- + Business proposals and quotes building in all import duties and markup rates

Graphic Designer // Paces Papers // Atlanta, GA // 2013-2016

- + Custom design services, including invitation suites, logos, marketing collateral, menus, campaign materials
- + Print preflight and oversight: digital, letterpress, engraved, single process color, silkscreen and apparel/gifts
- + Digital marketing design, launch and management for the store's marketing and social media platforms

Senior Digital Producer // Grey // New York, NY // 2012-2013

- + Lead digital project manager on the Canon EOS account
- + Managed all digital extensions for the Project Imaginat10n contest, including the development of a fully responsive website, custom CMS and all digital advertising/social media content
- + Resource management for creative and technology team within the \$4 million digital campaign budget

Senior Project Manager // DraftFCB // New York, NY // 2010-2012

- + Lead digital project manager on the Office of National Drug Control Policy, Fisher Price and Beiersdorf accounts
- + Primary digital producer for the general side of the agency, consulting on projects and scope across a range of clients and new business proposals
- + Strategy and internal process for launching, managing & optimizing full social media campaigns

Senior Account Manager & Digital Producer // WDDG // New York, NY // 2007-2008

- + Lead client contact and project manager for the creative execution of digital marketing campaigns, sweepstakes and new business
- + Clients: Marc Ecko, Marc Jacobs, Zoo York, Coty Beauty, Wrigley's Candystand
- + Information architecture, wireframes and sitemaps for 100+ page websites
- + Managed internal creative and production teams on concurrent projects (12-15 people)

Digital Producer // Deutsch Inc. // New York, NY // 2005-2007

- + Lead digital producer the Tylenol account, overseeing website updates, online media, promotions & sweepstakes
- + Managed resource allocation, staffing plans, scheduling, quality assurance & delivery prep on concurrent projects
- + Delivery & traffic of online media campaigns, rich media & sponsorship branding
- + Liaison between the Account Team & the Creative/Production Teams for several concurrent projects (8-12 people)

Account Manager & Project Manager // 65media // Los Angeles, CA // 2003-2005

- + Managed the creative execution of internet marketing campaigns for entertainment clients
- + Coordinated creative, production & programming teams on concurrent projects (15-18 people)
- + Clients: Disney, Pixar, Paramount, 20th Century Fox, Touchstone, Focus, Muppets Holding Co.
- + Wrote and designed new business proposals, script summaries & creative site copy
- + Creative brainstorm facilitator for client pitches & project development
- Developed online creative concepts to compliment & expand the studio's marketing campaign

EDUCATION

UNDERGRADUATE: Texas Christian University | Fort Worth, TX | Radio-TV-Film | 1998-2002

DESIGN SCHOOL: Parsons The New School for Design | New York, NY | Graphic Design | 2008–2009

USER EXPERIENCE: General Assembly | Atlanta, GA | UX Design | 2016

SOFTWARE SKILLS & METHODOLOGIES

Photoshop - Illustrator - InDesign - Office - Visio - Microsoft Project - Basecamp - Keynote - Slack - Trello - HubSpot - HootSuite - Agile - Scrum - Wordpress - MailChimp - Constant Contact - Squarespace